Guide to the Consumer Reports. Advocacy records, 1927-2011 and undated RL.11780
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Statements, Comments, Testimonies, etc., 1954-2001 and undated; 3
  - 1992, 28
    - 9206003-1. Federal Home Loan Bank System, 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9206004-2. Sold Short: The Actual Cost of a Minimum Adequate Living Standard Compared to AFDC Levels in California, 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9207001-1. GATT (General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade), 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9207002-1. Mortgages, 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9208001-1. Product liability, 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9208002-1. Product liability, 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9210002-1. Carpet chemical emissions, 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9211001-1. NAFTA (North American Free Trade Agreement), 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9212001-1. Banks, 1992 (Box 13)
    - 9212002-2. The Health Care Crisis in the Latino Community, 1992 (Box 13)
  - 1993, 29
    - 9300001-1. Health Care Security for All: The Single-Payer Answer, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9300002-2. Consumer Finance Law Quarterly Report, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9300003-2. The Thin Red Line: How the Poor Still Pay More, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9300004-3. Environmental equity, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9300005-0. Living Soils: Sustainable Alternatives to Chemical Fertilizers, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9300006-0. Sustainable Agriculture and Rural Development, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9302001-1. Credit, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9303001-1. Beverages, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9304001-0. Health Care in Crisis: Building a System that Works for Consumers, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9305001-1. Home ownership, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9305002-1. Credit, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9305003-1. Federal Trade Commission, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9305004-1. Medical malpractice, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9306001-1. Medical care, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9306002-1. Insurance, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9307001-1. Insurance, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9310001-1. Insurance, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9310002-1. Credit, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9311001-1. Insurance, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9311002-1. Insurance, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9311003-1. How Health Care Reform Will Affect Senior Citizens, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9312001-2. Mortgages, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9312002-1. The Clinton Health Care Act, 1993 (Box 13)
    - 9312004-1. The Clinton Health Care Act, 1993 (Box 13)
  - 1994, 30
    - 9400001-2. Uniform Commercial Code, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9400002-2. Uniform Commercial Code, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9400003-0. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9401001-1. How Health Care Reform Will Affect Children, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9401002-1. Health security, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9402001-1. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9402002-1. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9403001-1. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9403002-0. Growth hormones in cattle, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9403003-0. Growth hormones in cattle, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9403004-0. Growth hormones in cattle, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9403005-0. Growth hormones in cattle, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9403006-0. Growth hormones in cattle, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9404001-0. Genetically engineered foods, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9404002-1. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9405001-1. Medical devices, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9405002-2. Check-cashing industry, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9405003-1. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9406001-2. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9407001-1. Alternative medicine, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9408001-1. Banks, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9409001-1. Child Safety Protection Act, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9409002-0. Growth hormones in cattle, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9409003-1. Automobile insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9410001-1. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9410002-1. GATT (General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade), 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9410003-1. Insurance, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9410004-1. Automobile rollover standard, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9411001-1. Speaking Out: Consumers Union's Key Health Care Testimony, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9411002-1. Letters to Congress: Consumers Union and Health Care Reform, 1994 (Box 13)
    - 9412001-1. Consumers Union's Role in the Health Care Debate of 1993-1994 (Box 13)
  - 1995, 31
    - 9502001-0. Environmental protection (packaging, recycling), 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9502002-0. Growth hormones in cattle, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9502004-1. Product liability, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9502005-1. Medicare (insurance), 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9503001-2. Consumer protection, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9503002-1. Community reinvestment, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9503003-1. Banks, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9504001-1. Meat industry, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9505001-0. Hazardous substances, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9505002-1. Insurance, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9505003-1. Insurance, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9505004-1. Regulatory reform, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9505005-1. Regulatory reform, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9505006-0. Chemical accidents, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9506001-3. Contact lenses, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9506002-1. Insurance, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9506003-1. Federal employee charitable donations, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9506004-0. DEET, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9506005-0. DEET, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9510001-1. Postmark Prompt Payment Act, 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9510002-0. Perchloroethylene (dry cleaning industry), 1995 (Box 13)
    - 9511001-2. Home equity loans, 1995 (Box 13)
  - 1996, 32
    - 9600001-0. Pest Management at the Crossroads, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9600002-0. Progress and Roadblocks: Sustainable Agriculture at FAO and the World Bank, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9601001-1. Nursing homes, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9604001-1. Medical care, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9605001-1. Mortgages, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9606001-1. Banks, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9606002-1. Medical savings accounts, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9606003-1. EBT (Electronic Balance Transfers) program, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9607001-0. Perchloroethylene (dry cleaning industry), 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9607002-1. Insurance, 1996 (Box 13)
    - 9610001-2. Banks, 1996 (Box 13)
  - 1997, 33
    - 9700001-1. Banks, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9700002-2. Uniform Commercial Code, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9700003-2. A Manual on the Conversion of Nonprofit Health Care Organizations into For-Profit Corporations, 1997; 2 folders (Box 14)
    - 9701001-0. Pesticides, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9701002-1. 25th anniversary of Washington Office of CU, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9702001-1. HIPAA (Health Insurance Portability and Accountability Act), 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9702002-1. Banks, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9702003-1. Automobile air bags, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9702004-1. Mortgages, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9703001-1. Telecommunications, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9703002-1. Insurance, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9704001-1. Cable television, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9704002-0. Insurance, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9704003-0. Insurance, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9707001-1. Air transport, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9707002-1. Banks, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9707003-3. Banks, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9709001-1. Cable television, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9709002-1. Debit cards, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9709003-1. Telecommunications, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9709004-2. Uniform Commercial Code, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9710001-1. Antitrust, 1997 (Box 14)
    - 9712001-3. Moving industry, 1997 (Box 14)
  - 1998, 34
    - 9801001-1. Hidden from View: The Growing Burden of Health Care Costs, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9802001-0. Pesticides, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9802002-1. Telecommunications, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9802003-3. Mortgages, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9804001-1. Banks, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9804002-1. Food safety, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9805001-0. Personal privacy, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9805002-1. Telecommunications, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9805003-3. Telecommunications, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9806001-1. Telecommunications, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9807001-1. Medical savings accounts, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9807002-1. Public utilities, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9807003-3. Preserving the Charitable Trust: Nonprofit Hospital Conversion in Texas, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9809001-1. Telecommunications, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9809002-1. Pesticides, 1998 (Box 14)
    - 9811001-3. Break the Dam: Access to Public Information in Texas, 1998 (Box 14)
  - 1999, 35
    - 9902001-1. Automobile safety standards, 1999 (Box 14)
    - 9904001-2. White Knights or Trojan Horses? A Policy and Legal Framework for Evaluating Hospital Consolidations in California, 1999 (Box 14)
    - 9904002-3. Looking Back at the Promises of Medicaid Managed Care (insurance), 1999 (Box 14)
    - 9906001-2. Manage to Care: How California Can Better Inform Consumers About Managed Care, 1999 (Box 14)
    - 9908001-2. There's No Place Like Home: The Implications of Reverse Mortgages on Seniors in California, 1999 (Box 14)
    - 9909001-2. Balancing Mission and Market: Nonprofits Walk a Tightrope Between the Public and Private Spheres, 1999 (Box 14)
    - 9912001-2. The Tie That Binds: Linking Children's Health Insurance with School Nutrition Programs in California, 1999 (Box 14)
  - 2000, 36
    - 0000001-2. Philanthropy (Building Strong Foundations), 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0002001-0. Ephedrine, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0003001-2. A Golden Opportunity: Improving Children's Health Through California's Schools, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0003002-2. Healthy Kids Healthy Schools, 2000 (Box 18)
    - 0003003-1. Television broadcast licenses, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0003004-1. Radio, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0004001-1. AOL/Time Warner merger, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0004002-1. AOL/Time Warner merger, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0004003-1. Television broadcast licenses, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0004004-1. Low-power radio, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0004005-1. Telecommunications, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0004007-1. Sub-prime and prime mortgage lending in Texas, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0005001-0. Waste management in New York, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0005002-3. Livestock industry in Texas, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0005003-1. AOL/Time Warner merger, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0005004-1. Credit cards, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0006001-2. Good as Gold: Preserving Community Resources in Nonprofit Conversions, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0006002-0. Medical financial privacy, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0007001-1. Online travel agencies (Orbitz), 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0007002-1. MediaOne/AT&T, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0008001-2. EBT (Electronic Balance Transfers) program, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0008002-0. Automobile rollover standard, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0009001-1. Computer reservations, 2000 (Box 14)
    - 0010001-3. Pre-paid funerals in Texas, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0011001-1. MediaOne/AT&T, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0012001-0. Child automobile restraints (Box 14)
    - 0012002-3. Railroad Commission, 2001 (Box 14)
  - 2001, 37
    - 0101002-0. Tire identification markings, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0101003-1. High-speed internet, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0101004-3. Price to Beat program (fuel charges--Texas), 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0102001-0. 1996 Telecommunications Act (Box 14)
    - 0101005-3. Telephone monopolies, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0102002-3. Natural gas, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0102003-3. Natural gas, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0102004-3. Contact lenses, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0102005-3. Mobile home tenants' rights, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103001-3. Railroad Commission, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103002-3. Manufactured housing, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103003-3. Prescription drug costs, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103004-3. Drug purchasing cooperatives, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103005-3. Medicaid, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103006-3. Medicaid, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103007-3. Kids insurance program, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0103008-3. Pesticides, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0104001-3. Railroad Commission, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0104002-3. Privacy of information, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0104003-3. Medical privacy, 2001 (Box 14)
    - 0104004-3. Medicaid, 2001 (Box 14)
  - Miscellaneous, 1974-1991 and undated; 38
    - 1900008-0. Environmental Problems of Chemical Fertilizer Use (Hugh McGuinness), 1991 (Box 14)
    - ND064-2. Dairy products, 1976 (Box 14)
    - ND068-2. Conflict of interest, 1976 (Box 18)
    - ND069-2. CPA monopoly in California, undated (Box 18)
    - ND070-1. Bank services, undated (Box 14)
    - ND071-1. Bank accounts, undated (Box 14)
    - ND072-1. Qualifications for Optometrists Board--Virginia, 1976 (Box 14)
    - ND073-0. Television advertising to children, 1978 and undated; 3 folders (Box 14)
    - ND074-1. Physicians' services, 1976 (Box 15)
    - ND075-1. Specialization of lawyers, 1976 (Box 15)
    - ND076-1. Cable television, 1977 (Box 15)
    - ND077-2. Product promotion in schools, 1976 (Box 15)
    - ND078-1. Children's cereal, 1977 (Box 15)
    - ND079-1. Use of "All" and "Pure" on product labels, 1974 (Box 15)
    - ND080-3. Termination of utility services--Texas, undated (Box 15)
    - ND081-1. Lawyers, 1980 (Box 15)
    - ND082-1. Lawyers, 1979 (Box 15)
    - ND083-1. Lawyers, 1978 (Box 15)
    - ND084-1. Credit rights, undated (Box 15)
    - ND085-1. Moving industry, 1980 (Box 15)
    - ND086-1. Debt collectors, undated (Box 18)
    - ND087-1. Balloons, 1974 (Box 15)
    - ND088-1. Balloons, undated (Box 15)
    - ND089-1. Food dating, undated (Box 15)
    - ND090-1. Small claims courts, undated (Box 15)
    - ND091-1. Small claims courts, undated (Box 15)
    - ND092-1. Small claims courts, undated (Box 15)
    - ND093-1. Small claims courts, undated (Box 15)
    - ND094-0. Gasoline, 1979 (Box 15)
    - ND095-0. Credit insurance, 1979 (Box 15)
    - ND096-0. Insurance redlining, undated (Box 15)
    - ND097-2. Prescription drug costs, undated (Box 15)
    - ND098-1. Life jackets, undated (Box 15)
    - ND099-0. Natural gas, undated (Box 15)
    - ND100-1. Tomatoes, undated (Box 15)
    - ND101-1. School lunch programs, undated (Box 18)
    - ND102-0. School lunch programs, undated (Box 15)
    - ND103-0. School lunch programs, undated (Box 15)
    - ND104-1. Public Service Commission, undated (Box 15)
    - ND105-1. Lawyers, 1980 (Box 15)
    - ND106-1. Lawyers, undated (Box 15)
    - ND107-1. Government accounting, undated (Box 15)
    - ND108-1. Contractor liability, undated (Box 15)
    - ND109-2. Money and Politics (CU publication), 1986 (Box 15)
    - ND110-2. Promoting Health Protecting Privacy (publication--California), undated (Box 15)
    - ND112-0. Social Costs of Modern Agriculture (Hugh McGuinness), 1991 (Box 15)
- Consumer Policy Activities, 1981-2004
  - Consumer Policy Institute, 1988-2004
    - Information packet--FAO/Netherlands Conference on Agriculture and the Environment, 1991 (Box 19)
    - Preliminary Analysis: 1990 Toxic Chemical Air Pollution from Industry in New York City, 1992 (Box 19)
    - Reaching for Zero: The Citizens Plan for Zero Waste in NYC (Resa Dimino, Barbara Warren), 2004 (Box 19)
    - Taking Out the Trash: A New Direction for New York City's Waste (Barbara Warren), 2000 (Box 19)
    - The "HELP" Survey: A Survey of Emergency Planning Committees in New Jersey, 1988 (Box 19)
    - Toward a Toxic Free Environment (Eileen Nic, editor), 1990 (Box 19)
    - Toward a Toxic Free Environment in New Jersey (Eileen Nic, editor), 1990 (Box 19)
    - Toxic Air Pollution from New York City Industry (Eileen Nic and Beth Inabinett), 1990 (Box 19)
  - Institute for Consumer Policy Research, 1981-1991
    - Action Kit: Lead Hazards and Children, 1990-1991 (Box 19)
    - Advance Notice newsletter, 1981-1983 (Box 19)
    - Caregiver's Resource Kit, 1987 (Box 19)
    - Caring at Home for Older Patients with Late-Stage Cancer (Margaret Gold), 1985 (Box 19)
    - Ethics and Values in Food Safety Regulation (conference papers), 1984; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Information packet--Poverty conference, 1986 (Box 20)
    - Life Support: Families Speak About Hospitals, Hospice and Home Care for the Fatally Ill (Margaret Gold), 1983 (Box 20)
    - Violating the Pesticide Code: A Survey of Indonesia, the Philippines and Thailand (IOCU), 1987 (Box 20)
  - Michael Hansen Research Papers, 1987-2001
    Biographical / Historical
    Michael Hansen was a Research Associate at Consumers Union, specializing in biotechnology issues. He has served as advisor for the United States Department of Agriculture, the United Nations' Food and Agriculture Organization, and World Health Organization.
    - Escape from the Pesticide Treadmill (versions in English, Indonesian and Spanish), 1988-1990; 3 folders (Box 20)
    - Genetically Engineered Food: Make Sure It's Safe and Label It, 2001 (Box 20)
    - Progress and Roadblocks: Sustainable Agriculture at FAO and the World Bank (with Robbin Blaine), 1996 (Box 20)
    - Sustainable Agriculture and Rural Development: FAO at the Crossroads, 1993 (Box 20)
    - The First Three Years: Implementation of the World Bank Pesticide Guidelines 1985-1988, 1990 (Box 20)
    - Violating the Pesticide Code: A Preliminary Survey of Indonesia, the Philippines and Thailand (with Sarojini Rengam), 1987 (Box 20)